在2007的五月 Lily阿姨和Marshall叔叔结婚了
In May of 2007, Aunt Lily and Uncle Marshall got married
就在纽约州北部具有历史意义的 Van Smoot House
at the historic Van Smoot House in upstate New York.
哇，好漂亮，Lily
Wow, it's beautiful, Lily.
没错，就跟我一直想要的一样
Yeah. It's just how I always pictured it.
最好你本来就这么想
Well, that was a load of crap.
孩子们，当你要结婚了 你会学到宝贵的一课
You see, kids, when you get married, you learn a hard lesson.
你一开始打算办的婚礼 最终大都不会成真
The wedding you set out to have is almost never the wedding you end up with.
[婚礼前8个月] 所以，我们决定办个小型的户外婚礼
So, we've decided on a small, outdoor wedding,
只请亲人和比较亲密的朋友
just family and close friends.
不超过25人
No more than 25 people
在某个漂亮的花园
in a beautiful garden somewhere,
也许当我们走在红毯上时
maybe an acoustic guitar playing
可以用原音吉他伴奏
while we walk down the aisle.
也许你们已知道有谁到了法院
And maybe you already know someone who went down to the courthouse
注册成为司仪
and registered as an officiant
他或者她，还是他--
so that he or she-- he--
可以主持仪式
could perform the ceremony.
但你恨婚姻，你怎么会想主持婚礼？
But you hate marriage. Why do you want to perform the ceremony?
因为那会在无声无息下 灌输一个想法到每个在场的女性脑中
Because it subtly implants in the mind of every woman there
那就是当我问什么问题时
that when I ask a question,
都要说 "我愿意"
you say, "I do."
没错
Yeah.
[婚礼前6个月] 你越接近那个大日子
The closer you get to the big day,
就会做出越多的让步
the more concessions you make.
太好了，我妈要我邀请Lessners一家
Great. Now my mom's making me invite the Lessners.
那会让宾客数到达3位数
This puts our numbers in the triple digits.
哇，我想有时Lessner反而代表"比较多" (Less是较少之意)
Wow. I guess sometimes, Lessner is more... ner.
你知道有时候"较少反而是较多" 是怎么样的情况
You know how like sometimes less is more.
没错，现在就是了，是吧，宝贝？
Yeah. This is one of those times, sweetie?
你知道吗？没关系 这只代表这会是个有点大的户外婚礼
You know what? That's okay. It'll be a slightly big outdoor wedding.
[婚礼前5个月] 所以不办户外婚礼了
So it's not going to be an outdoor wedding anymore.
Marshall的老爸听信人家说 在纽约办户外婚礼
Marshall's dad is convinced if we have an outdoor wedding in New York,
他会被抢劫，所以要改在室内
he's going to get mugged, so it's going to be inside now.
会很棒的，我们还是可以用原音吉他伴奏
It'll be great. We're still going to have our acoustic guitar player.
[婚礼前3个月] 所以不用原音吉他
So now, instead of an acoustic guitar,
要改用竖琴
we're having a harp player.
我爸欠一个家伙人情... 那家伙的女儿会弹竖琴
Yeah. My dad owes a guy, and... that guy's daughter plays the harp.
她正点吗？我很乐意从我的清单中 除去"竖琴手"这一项
Is she hot? I'd love to be able to cross "harp player" off my list.
那清单有多长？
How long is this list?
老兄，我可不打算去数那清单有几张
Dude, I'm not gonna count how many pages the list is.
我不是笨蛋
I'm not crass.
无论如何，那无所谓，因为她怀孕了
Well, it doesn't matter anyway. She's pregnant.
太好了！我可以划掉两个项目
Sweet! I can cross off two things.
老爸老妈的浪漫史 第二季第二十一集
Transcript: Raceman
译者：Bug Li
Subtitles: Willow's Team
Lily和Marshall的超大室内婚礼那天来到...
And the day arrives for Lily and Marshall's very big indoor wedding...
[婚礼前1小时又42分] 伴随着竖琴
with a harp.
嗨，Lily
Hi, Lily.
哇，Andrea
Wow. Andrea.
你真的是怀孕了
You really are pregnant.
没错
Yeah.
你的腹部这么...你怎么弹？
How do you play the harp with your belly so...?
我没有真的要-- 我只能弹到大概一半的琴弦
Oh, I don't really-- I can only reach about half the strings.
你要只用半个竖琴来弹
You only play half the harp?
没错
Yeah.
哦，不，没关系，Lily，我会处理的
Oh, no. Uh, okay. Lily, I will take care of this.
我来弹另一半，这很难学吗？
Um, I'll just pluck the other half. Is it hard to learn?
我已经学了12年了
I've been studying the harp for 12 years.
不过我学东西很快
Yeah, but I'm a fast learner.
你有没有听过"吉他英雄"这游戏 我一天内就会玩了
You ever hear of "Guitar Hero"? Learned that in a day.
那有"竖琴英雄"吗？
Is there a "Harp Hero"?
Robin，没关系
Robin, it's fine.
那，你预产期是何时？
So, so, when are you due?
周二
Tuesday.
哇，那快到了
Wow, that's soon.
是上周二
Last Tuesday.
[婚礼前1小时又38分] 见鬼，我们得辞退她
Holy crap, we have to fire her.
她会在你的典礼到一半时 就生出一个小伙子来
She's gonna drop a shorty in the middle of your ceremony.
Robin，我不会让自己太不安
Robin, I'm not going to freak myself out.
我讨厌那些说
I hate those women who say,
"哦，我的婚礼一定要十全十美"的女人
"Oh, my wedding has to be perfect."
总是会出状况的 有时候是DJ放错歌了
Things go wrong. Sometimes the deejay screws up your playlist.
有时候你会在新人退场时 踩到胎盘滑倒
Sometimes you slip on placenta during the recessional.
能不能马上给我些威士忌苏打？
Can I grab a scotch and soda real quick?
不，在招待会前，我不能提供食物给人
No. I'm not allowed to serve anything until the reception.
哇，你刚刚少掉了一大笔的小费，兄弟
Wow. You just cost yourself a big tip, buddy.
我也不被允许接受小费，兄弟
I'm not allowed to accept tips, buddy.
那你有没有被允许接受批评？
You allowed to accept criticism?
你，先生，是只笨驴... 兄弟
You, sir, are an ass... buddy.
嘿，你们想知道什么搭讪词 对竖琴手没有作用吗？
Hey, you want to know what line doesn't work on a harp player?
"嘿，宝贝，要弹(吹)吗？" (pluck有弹乐器之意，但也有口交之意)
"Hey, baby, want to pluck?"
真的？那没有用？
Really? That didn't work.
连一点用都没有
Not even a little.
嘿！Bill是谁啊？
Hey! Who's Bill?
Bill？
Bill?
对啊，这家伙在酒吧跟我讲话
Yeah. This guy came up to me at the bar.
我能请问你些事吗？
Can I ask you something?
典礼中是什么时候他们会问有没有人反对？
Where in the ceremony is the place where they ask if anyone objects?
呃... 我想他们好像不再这么做了
Uh... Don't think they do that anymore.
那你认为什么时候比较好？
Oh, so when do you think someone should do it?
是等休息时间的时候还是？
Just wait for a lull or what?
哦，不
Oh, no.
你看到的是不是一个想要成为裁判 但是没有成功的人？
Did he look like a guy who tried to be an umpire but failed?
的确有点像
He kind of did.
那就是Scooter
That's Scooter.
你的高中男友，Scooter？
Your high school boyfriend, Scooter?
他的真名叫Bill
His real name is Bill.
我妈一定邀请他了
My mom must have invited him.
为什么？她为什么要这么做？
Why? Why would she do that?
我们两家关系很亲密
Our families are really close.
但是邀我的前男友？
But my ex-boyfriend?
拜托，老妈
Come on, Mom.
我可没有邀请老爸抓到 跟你在一起的那个职业壁球选手
I didn't invite that professional squash player Dad busted you with.
哦，我需要杯酒
Oh, I need a glass of wine.
我去拿
I'll get it.
哦，谢了，嘿，Marshall还好吧？
Oh, thanks. Hey, how's Marshall doing?
他很好
He's great.
他就要去剪头发了
He's about to get his hair cut.
哦，我很担心我的侄子会剪得太短
Oh. I'm worried my cousin's going to cut it too short.
我也是，我整晚睡不着
Me, too. I was up all night.
嗨，Lily
Hello, Lily.
嘿，Bill
Hey, Bill.
嘿，Barney
Hey, Barney.
Scooter，你来这里干什么？
Scooter, what are you doing here?
我不再叫"Scooter"了
It's not "Scooter" anymore.
叫我Bill
It's Bill.
我变了很多，Lily
A lot of things have changed about me, Lily,
但有一点没变
but one hasn't.
我还是爱着你
I still love you.
我来这里就是要赢回你的心
And I came here to win you back.
你真是可爱，哦，不，是真的吗？
You're really cute. Oh, no. Really?
Lily，我知道这样很疯狂
Lily, I-I know it's crazy,
但我爱你
but I love you,
如果你能看着我的眼睛
and if you can look me in the eye
告诉我你想嫁给Marshall
and tell me that you want to marry Marshall,
我马上离开，永远离开你的生命
I will leave right now and be out of your life forever.
我想...
I want...
Scooter！
Scooter!
我需要杯酒
I need a glass of wine.
而我需要你立刻从我眼前消失
And I need you to get out of my face.
是给新娘的，所以...
It's for the bride, so...
白酒还是红酒？
White or red?
白酒
White.
还有，她也想要点威士忌苏打
And, uh... she'd also like a scotch and soda.
马上来
You got it.
她还想要盘烟熏杏仁
She'd also like a bowl of smoked almonds.
我这里没有
I don't have any,
但我想我可以跑到外面转角去买一些
but I guess I could run out to the corner and get some.
只不过这是她人生中最重大的日子，所以...
Well, it's only the biggest day of her life, so...
游戏开始了
Let the games begin.
[婚礼前47分] 给，不能久留，有些事想试试
Here. Can't stay. Got to try something.
也许我的话没法改变你的心意
Maybe my words won't change your mind,
但也许一首诗可以
but maybe the words of a poet will.
我在"November Rain"读到的 ("枪与玫块"乐团的歌曲)
I read from "November Rain."
W. Axl Rose所写 (该乐团成员)
By W. Axl Rose.
那是首好歌
That is a good song.
Barney说你需要我赶走 一个叫Scooter的家伙？
Barney said you needed me to bounce some guy named Scooter?
Bill怎么了？
What's up with Bill?
那就是Scooter
That's Scooter.
交给我了
I'm on it.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
我能要你的电话号码吗？
Can I have your phone number?
不行
No.
给新娘的
It's for the bride.
哦，等等，我拿支笔
Oh. Hold on. Let me go get a pen.
新娘要你走路走慢点
The bride wants you to walk slower.
[婚礼前40分]
哦，哇
Oh, wow.
哦，Robin...
Oh. Robin...
我的妆看来很完美
My makeup looks perfect right now,
但我要哭了，想想办法吧
and I'm about to cry. Do something.
我的乳头很多毛
I have hairy nipples.
真的？
Really?
假的，但真的有用，不是吗？
No, but it worked, didn't it?
嘿，有件事很好笑
Hey. Funny story.
我扭倒一个我以为是Scooter的人
I tackled this guy I thought was Scooter.
结果那是你的摄影师
Turns out it was your photographer.
别担心，我有这支很棒的照相手机 所以不会有问题的
Don't worry. I got this sweet camera phone, so we're covered.
有摄影师？
There's a photographer?
哦，天啊
Oh, my God.
- 没关系，我只要打电话给... - Robin，停，停
- Okay, I just have to call... - Robin, stop. Stop.
没关系的
It's okay.
今天我不会让任何事情影响到我
I am not gonna let anything get to me today.
[婚礼前33分] 我刚接到花店的电话
I just got a call from the florist. The flowers won't be here
花要到典礼中才会到
till halfway through the ceremony.
我没事
I'm okay.
[婚礼前28分] 不是故意要打扰你，但是... 我想我在停车场捡到你的面纱
I hate to bother you, but... I think I found your veil in the parking lot.
我没事
I'm fine.
[婚礼前24分]
只是让你知道一下，我的羊水破了
Just FYI: my water broke.
但我也许可以...
But I can probably...
...撑过去
...make it through.
完全没关系
Totally cool.
[婚礼前21分]
哦，不
Oh, no.
Lily，我想我忘了带你的婚礼内裤
Lily, I think I forgot your bridal panties.
我以为我带了，实在很抱歉
I-I thought I had them. I'm so sorry.
没关系，我穿现在穿的这件就好
Oh, it's okay, I'll just wear the ones I have on.
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
今天我要嫁给Marshall了
I'm marrying Marshall today.
所以就算我要没戴头纱走过红毯
So it doesn't even matter that I'm gonna walk down the aisle
在一个没有花的房间里
without a veil in a room that has no flowers
音乐是一个正在分娩的女人 弹着半支竖琴
to the music of half a harp played by a woman who's crowning,
同时我的高中男友念着"枪与玫瑰"的歌词
as my high school boyfriend reads Guns N' Roses lyrics.
那都没关系
But that's okay,
因为根本也没摄影师在场 能照下任何照片
because there's no photographer there to take any pictures of it anyway.
Lily，你还好吗？
Lily, are you okay?
你觉得呢？！我当然不好！
What do you think?! Of course I'm not okay!
所有我的婚礼上可能发生的状况都发生了
Everything that could possibly go wrong at my wedding has!
一切都被破坏了！
It's ruined!
你不是说"我不会想要一个完美婚礼"？
What happened to "I don't want a perfect wedding"?
成熟点吧，Robin 我当然想要完美的婚礼！
Oh, grow up, Robin! Of course I want a perfect wedding!
哦，天啊，我本想... 我本想不要太在意婚礼的，但是...
Oh, God. I wanted... I wanted not to care about the wedding, but...
我很在意，我今天应该要感觉像公主一样
I do. I... I'm supposed to feel like a princess today.
你会的
And you will.
不会有事的，宝贝
It's gonna be okay, sweetie.
我为何不到外面去？ 我有样东西可以让你好过点
Why don't we go outside? I have something that'll make you feel better.
你有什么东西可能让我好过点？
What could you have that could possibly make me feel better?
天啊，希望Marshall今天过得比我好
God, I hope Marshall's having a better day than I'm having.
哦，我的天啊，我的天啊
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
- 我的天啊！ - 怎么了？
- Oh, my God! - What?
不是太短
Well, it's not too short.
[婚礼前17分]
我的头发，瞧我的头发！ 她把我的头发毁了
My hair! Look at my hair! She ruined my hair!
我看起来好像是"新好男孩"的成员 (90年代很红的男孩团体)
I look like one of the Backstreet Boys!
的确很像
You totally do.
而且甚至不是好的新好男孩
And not even the good Backstreet Boys,
是比较老，跳着差劲舞步 复出巡回演唱的新好男孩
the older, lame dance move, comeback tour Backstreet Boys.
好的"新好男孩"？
The good Backstreet Boys?
我该怎么办？！
Guys! Guys! What am I gonna do?!
你到底发生什么事？
What-what the hell happened to you?
Lily的侄子上美容学院
Lily's cousin is in beauty school,
Lily不想要她弄她的头发
and Lily didn't want her to do her hair,
所以跟她说她可以弄我的
so she said she could do mine.
不要太短就好，可以吧？
So, um, just not-not too short, okay?
我们甚至一点都不用剪
Oh, no, we don't even have to cut it at all.
可以造型一下就好
Could just give it some style.
那就太好了
Oh, okay, yeah, that's great.
因为要是太短，就会看来很怪
'Cause, um, when it gets too short, it starts to look weird.
我可不想在那个时候看起来很怪
And I don't want to look weird when I'm up there, you know.
我可以给你弄很酷的挑染 (tips挑染，也有提示建议之意)
Ooh, I could give you some cool guy tips.
我不认为我要当一个酷哥 会需要人家的建议
I don't think I need advice on how to be cool,
但也好，就弄吧
but yeah, great, lay that on me.
我不能像这样结婚，不行！
I can't get married like this! There's no way!
让我看看我能怎么办
Ah, let me see what I can do.
什么？你能怎么办？
What? What can you do?
我有超能力的
I have a superpower.
Lily会杀了我的！
Lily is gonna kill me!
瞧我！
Look at me!
她不会想嫁给像这样的我
She's not gonna want to marry me like this.
别傻了，她当然愿意
That's crazy. Of course she will.
那你愿意跟我结婚吗？
Would you marry me?
不，不过不是因为头发 是因为我有个原则：
No. But not because of the hair. It's because I have a rule:
绝不跟曾一起比赛过放屁的人结婚
never marry anyone you've had a farting contest with.
太好了，所以你现在是说Lily和我 根本不应该结婚？
Oh, great. So now you're saying Lily and I shouldn't even get married?
大家注意我这边好吗？
Could I have everyone's attention, please?
是跟新娘有关的
It's for the bride.
首先，新娘希望...
One, the bride would...
我肩上所有压力能释放一下
like all of this tension out of my shoulders.
而她想要
And she would like, let's say,
穿着不合宜的短裙的你帮忙消除一下
you in the inappropriately short dress to rub them.
第二...
Two...
第二点是什么？
What was two?
好的，我们是出了点小状况
Okay, we have a bit of a situation.
不要太惊慌
Let's not panic.
试着找解决办法
Let's just find a solution.
老兄，你剃了你的头发
Dude, you shaved your freakin' head.
没错，但那很好
Yeah, yeah, but it's good.
我应该把它剃光光 真是个很好的解决方法
I ought to shave it all off. What a great solution.
光头很酷，对吧？
Just be bald 'cause it's cool, right?
布鲁斯威利，乔丹，还有小甜甜布兰妮... (布兰妮前阵子被看到剃了个大光头)
Bruce Willis, Michael Jordan, Britney Spears...
天啊，我做了什么？
Oh, God, what did I do?!
你怎么能让我剃我自己的头发？
How could you let me shave my head?!
- 什么？！ - 你真是史上最差劲的伴郎！
- What?! - You're the worst best man ever!
我恨你！
I hate you!
我不出去见人了！ 我要离开，永远不再回来
I'm not going out there! I'm leaving and I'm never coming back.
我要去找出放在那棵树旁岩石下的钱
I'm gonna go find that money under the rock by the tree
去跟Zihautanejo海滩的那家伙一起住 (这两句其实是"申肖克的救赎"的结局 台译片名是"刺激1995")
and go live with the guys on the beach in Zihautanejo.
老兄，他们是罪犯
Dude, those guys are criminals.
只有Red是，Andy是被冤枉的 (前述电影的主角)
Only Red Andy was falsely accused.
Ted，你是我的伴郎！ 你得想想办法
Ted, you're my best man! You got to do something!
没事的，过来，深呼吸一下，好吗？
Okay, all right, come here. Just breathe, breathe, all right?
别担心，别担心
Don't worry. Don't worry.
- 这个我拿着 - 不要！
- I'll just... I'll take these. - No!
- 嗨，Ben叔叔是吧？ - 是的
- Uh, hi. Uncle Ben, right? - Yes.
我们在后面有一点点小麻烦
Yes, we're, we're having a little bit of a problem back there.
你在想你能不能帮个忙
Um, and I was wondering if you could help us out.
可以啊
Yeah.
Marshall不小心剃掉了他部份的头发
Marshall accidentally shaved part of his head.
- 哦，不！ - 没错
- Oh, no! - Yeah.
所以我是这么想的
Yeah, so here's what I was thinking.
要是我能找到什么来遮着剃光的地方？
What if I found something to cover up the bald area?
没错，那就太好了
Yeah, that would probably work,
但是用什么呢？
but with what?
这是个难题
That's a tough one.
也许是顶假发
Maybe a wig of some sort or a, um...
像是男性假发
toupee.
某个符合他头发颜色的东西
Something that matches his hair color,
那也刚好有点像你头上头发的颜色
which is, which is kind of the same color as the top of your hair.
是喔
Mm, yeah.
但这里有谁戴假发？
Does anyone here wear a toupee?
应该不难找到
Shouldn't be hard to find out.
大部份都是很差的
Most of them are pretty bad.
没有错，没有错
That is true. That is true.
我们只要找到某个戴着
We just need to find someone who wears a toupee
和Marshall的及你的头发
that is the same color
一样颜色的假发的人
as Marshall's and your hair.
孩子，那真是很困难的事
Boy, that's a pretty tall order.
真的？
Really?
你难道想不到任何地方
You can't think of any place in the general area
可能会有我跟你描述的那样的假发？
where there might be a toupee of the kind I'm describing to you?
不，除非是我头上...
No, not off the top of my...
不，不行
No. Can't.
让我们从另一个角度来谈这件事 我的口袋里有50块钱
Let me come at this from a different angle. I got $50 in my pocket
- 那可能比... - 新娘需要这个
- which is probably a lot more... - The bride needs this.
[婚礼前13分]
我想真的有点用
Actually, I think it kinda works.
的确
It totally does.
Barney？
Barney?
老实说，我
To be honest, I'm, uh,
我没有机会戴，感到很羡慕
I'm jealous I don't get to wear it.
好了，问题解决了
Okay, problem solved.
危机解除了
Crisis averted.
可以结婚了
Let's get me married.
看起来糟透了，是不是？
It looks terrible, doesn't it?
那有点
It kinda looks like fur,
让你看起来像是梳洗整洁的"大脚" (外型类似雪怪的传说生物)
which gives you the appearance of a cleaned-up Bigfoot.
- 哦，你知道... - 是不好的那一种像
- Oh, you know... - In a bad way.
嘿，很酷的头发，兄弟
Hey. Cool hair, bro.
你的衬衫怎么了
What happened to your shirt?
我扭倒那个办外烩的时候 沾上了酱汁
I got sauce on it when I tackled the caterer.
要不要再找件穿上？
You gonna put another shirt on?
不，我没关系
No, I'm good.
嘿，你们有看到Scooter吗？
Hey, you guys seen Scooter?
什么？什么？Scooter在这里？ 那家伙在我的婚礼中？
What? What? Scooter's here? That guy's at my wedding?
不会太久的，兄弟
Not for long, bro.
不会太久的
Not for long.
你知道吗？我需要点空气
Okay, you know what? I need some air.
我想我们应该出去走走
I think we should go for a walk, okay?
那可以掩盖掉问题
It would cover up the problem.
那是个节庆
It's festive
庆祝这个伟大的国家祖先留下的遗产
and it celebrates the heritage of this great nation.
好了，除非你真的有一顶在你的车上
Okay, unless you actually have one in your car,
不然就别再提议什么 "有认证的美洲原住民头饰"
stop suggesting authentic Native American headdress.
哦，不
Oh, no.
哦，我的天啊！
Oh, my God!
Marshall...
Lily，你不应该看见我的
Lily, you're not supposed to see me.
真见鬼了，我想任何人都不应该看到你
Holy crap, I don't think anyone's supposed to see you.
怎么了？Amy把你弄成这样的？
What happened? Did Amy do this to you?
只有挑染是，其余是我搞的 很抱歉，宝贝
Just the frosted tips. I did the rest. I'm sorry, baby.
我把个整个婚礼都毁了，是吧？
I've ruined the whole wedding, haven't I?
哦，不，你没有毁了婚礼，宝贝
Oh, no, you didn't ruin the wedding, sweetie.
它早就毁了
It was already ruined.
没有花，没有摄影师
There's no flowers, no photographer.
还有，Scooter也在这
Oh, and Scooter's here, by the way.
我知道，我听说了
Yeah, I know. I heard.
我的面纱被弄得乱七八糟 那个竖琴手在生孩子
My veil got thrashed, the harp player is in labor,
而我没有穿着我的婚礼内衣
and I'm not wearing my wedding underwear.
什么？ 没有后面写着"Marshall的财产"那件？
What? No "Property of Marshall" across the back?
那人家怎么知道那是谁的屁股？
How are people going to know whose butt that is?
怎么了？
What happened?
记得我们本来想要的婚礼 是秘密的户外婚礼吗？
Remember the wedding we wanted, the intimate outdoor ceremony?
真希望我们能办那样的婚礼
I wish we could have that wedding.
那就办啊
So do it.
什么？
What?
现在就结婚
Get married now.
就在这
Right here.
听我说，这里不就是你们想要的户外
Look, it's outside like you always wanted.
只有亲密的朋友
Intimate, close friends.
没有吉它，但很接近了
There's no guitar, but it's pretty close.
Barney可以主持仪式
Barney can officiate.
对，我可以
Yes. Yes, I can.
抱歉了各位，你们全都掉了样东西：
Uh, excuse me, guys. You all dropped something:
你们的下巴--
your jaws--
因为Barney Stinson就要做 一场婚礼的共犯
because Barney Stinson is about to aid and abet a marriage.
我们可以这么做吗？ 那在那里的那些人怎么办？
Could we even do that? I mean, what about all those people in there?
那边也办，然后要是出了什么状况
Do that one, too. And then when everything goes wrong,
你们就不会在意 因为真正的婚礼在这里办过了
you won't care because you already had the real wedding out here.
你怎么想，宝贝？
What do you think, baby?
我喜欢这个主意
I love it.
我也是
Me, too.
就这么做吧，让我们在结婚前结婚
Let's do it. Let's get married before we get married.
太好了
Great.
等等
Wait, hold on.
抱歉打扰一下，先生
Excuse me, sir.
我们可以借一下你的帽子吗？
Could we borrow your hat?
好的
Okay.
谢谢你
Thank you.
帽子
Hat.
我们在想到帽子之前
We thought of authentic Native American headdress
竟会先想到了"有认证的美洲原住民头饰"
before we thought of hat.
谢谢各位光临
Thank you all for coming.
怕在座有人不认识我...
For those of you who don't know me...
我并不是那种很相信婚姻的人
I'm not the biggest believer in marriage.
但是... 你们在一起真的很棒
But... you two are so great together, you know?
就好像，你们是为彼此而存在
It's like you were, uh, made for each other.
- 他要哭了 - 不，才没有
- He's gonna cry. - No, I'm not.
我没有，我没有，我没有...
I'm not, I'm not, I'm not, I'm not, I'm not.
Lily和Marshall...
Lily and Marshall...
当大家看到你们，他们...
when everyone sees you, they...
看见的是真爱
see true love.
最美的爱...
It's the best love...
我们可以... 直接跳到交换戒指之类的吗？
Can we just, um, move on to the rings or something?
不好了
Oh, no.
我没有带我的誓辞
I don't have my vows.
我也没有带我的
I don't have mine either.
你们不需要誓辞 只要说说为什么爱他/她
You don't need your vows. Just say why you love each other.
好，我先
Okay, I'll go first.
Lily
Lily,
我爱你有一百万种理由
there are a million reasons why I love you.
你让我笑
You make me laugh
当我生病时照顾我
and you take care of me when I'm sick.
你贴心，关心 甚至做了一道鸡蛋菜肴以我命名
You're sweet, caring and you even created an egg dish and named it after me.
她在炒松蛋之前，放了些意式沙拉酱在里面
She puts a little Italian dressing in scrambled eggs before she cooks them.
叫作"Marshall蛋"，而且那棒极了
It's called "Eggs Marshall," and it's awesome.
但我爱你最主要的理由是
But the main reason that I love you is
你是我最好的朋友，Lily
that you're my best friend, Lily.
你是... 我有过最好的朋友
You're, uh... you're the best friend I ever had.
- 抱歉了，兄弟 - 没问题
- I'm sorry, buddy. - No problem.
完全没关系
It's totally okay.
轮到我了
My turn.
哦，谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
Marshall，我爱你，因为你很有趣
Marshall, I love you because you're funny
你让我感到被爱
and you make me feel loved
让我感到安全
and you make me feel safe
而为了我们的周年纪念 你送了我一件汗衫，上面写点
and for our anniversary you gave me a sweatshirt that says,
"Lily和Marshall天下无双，自'96年开始"
"Lily and Marshall. Rockin' It Since '96."
我有点希望现在我是穿着它的
I kinda wish I was wearing it right now
因为那有你的味道
'cause it smells like you.
但我爱你最主要的理由 Marshall Ericksen
But the main reason I love you, Marshall Ericksen,
是你让我快乐
is you make me happy.
你总是让我快乐
You make me happy all the time.
嘿，我找到你的内裤了
Hey, I found your panties!
我没关系
I'm good.
Marshall，你愿意接受Lily成为你的妻子
Marshall, do you take Lily to be your wife to have and to hold from this day forward?
- 慢一点 - 我没办法
- Slow down. - I can't.
由今日起互相扶持，直到人生最后一天？
From this day forward so as long as you both shall live?
我愿意
I do.
Lily，你答应Marshall成为你的丈夫 并互相扶持... 一天？
Lily, do you promise to take Marshall to be your husband to have and to hold... live?
我愿意
I do.
好，那么
Okay, then,
以在Lafayette街的法院工作的 那个超刻薄的老巴基斯坦人
by the power invested in me by the very bitter old Pakistani man
所授予我的权力
who works down at the courthouse on Lafayette Street,
我现在宣布你们成为夫妻
I now pronounce you man and wife.
你可以亲吻新娘了
You may kiss the bride.
- 你抽烟吗？ - 不
- Do you smoke? - No.
哇，婚姻中的第一个谎言 还真是快
Wow. First lie of marriage. That was fast.
之后，我们都回到里面第二个婚礼
After that, we all went back inside for the second wedding.
而且，的确是有很多事情出错
And yes, a lot of things did go wrong,
但那都没有关系
but it didn't matter
因为当我回头看那一天
because when I look back on that day,
我所记得的就是第一个婚礼
what I remember is the first wedding;
那个私密的户外婚礼
the intimate outdoor ceremony
只有一些亲密的朋友在场
with just close friends
和一支原音吉他
and an acoustic guitar.
你觉得如何？
How do you feel?
好累，我今天结了两次婚
Tired. I got married twice today.
那我们第一次以已婚夫妻的身份做爱 你想在哪里呢？
So where do you want to do it for the first time as a married couple,
是舒适的饭店房间 还是接待大厅的厕所？
nice hotel room or a reception hall bathroom?
你怎么想？
What do you think?
当然是厕所
Bathroom, of course.
拜托不要
Please don't.
- 抱歉，Ted - 抱歉，Ted
- Sorry, Ted. - Sorry, Ted.
老爸老妈的浪漫史 第二季第二十一集 译者：Bug Li